Okay.
Hello, everyone.
Welcome to today's session.
My name is Rin Hao, and I'm very happy
to be here to bring you this topic about
the verification timing and why checking
AI-written code at the gate is already
too late today for coders in 2026.
So first, a little bit about myself.
My name is Rin Hao.
I studied in university and was
also a software engineer myself
in AWS for more than five years.
I was also, an early researcher
in AI, in natural language
processing, language models.
my first paper was published in 2017, and
when I was working in AWS, I also helped
them build the country testing framework.
Right now, it has more than almost
one million daily active users.
After AWS, I co-founded TestBright.
So right now, I'm more deep working
in the testing industry today.
And as we all know, in the past two
years, tools like CloudCode, Cursor,
Codex, also some coding, tools like
Lovable, Replicate, more for vibe
coders, for non-technical coders.
Lots of them are trending in the
market in the past two years, and
these tools have really made the
coding much easier than ever before.
But they also actually
introduce lots of new pains.
for example, right now, AI can
generate lots of content, can
generate lots of lines of code, but
sometimes it's a little bit too much.
A coding agent can run for hours and
are able to generate thousands or
even more lines of code at each time.
It's already making it nearly
impossible for users, coders, or
reviewers to manually go through
all these content one by one.
And also, even the best coding
agent today isn't 100% accurate.
They will make mistakes, due to
actually the latest benchmark.
I remember it's still 20 to 30%
times they will make some mistakes,
or maybe it will introduce some
bugs in the code that they generate.
Another thing that lots of people
ignored is that AI tends to lose track of
requirements due to their context window.
No context window right now holds
every requirement across long build,
especially those complex task.
Constraints will got dropped
in the middle of the task.
And nothing can bring them back
unless you remind of your coding
agent or maybe some other mechanism
remind them of what they are actually
initially reque-requested to do So, for
example, this is a diagram I think I,
actually fetched a couple months ago.
And I know, like in the past, even
two, three months, there are lots
of new coding agents, new models
that was released to the public.
But if we look at just those recent
data, we'll find out that there is a high
chance, roughly twenty to thirty percent
of the chances, the AI will make mistakes.
The only question is where that
bug is hidden in your code and when
the AI actually will make mistakes.
Imagine, I believe you already found
it, that lots of the PRs in your
today's code base are getting larger
and larger due to the AI is so fast
and so good at generating content.
This is a screenshot of
one PR in our company.
You can see it has almost forty thousand
lines of code that's been added into
the code base, and there are more than
fifty thousand lines of code that's
been removed from the code base.
So for such a big and huge PR,
how can we manually review it?
And to be very honest, do you
really want to review it, or are you
reviewing any PRs today yourself?
Yeah, I believe each of you have
different answers to this question,
but that question is leading us to
using lots of new mechanisms today.
People today are tends to use--
because manual reviewing is too hard,
so they are turning to let a machine
verify machine, let AI to review AI.
So for example, code review
by, AI companies, by AI agent
are very popular these days.
lots of companies are
offering that service.
we are letting coding agent to write
unit tests by themselves today as well.
We are also hearing lots of third-party
providers that can let their AI to
run integration tests for you so
that you can capture issues after
you finish all those coding tasks.
But each of those mechanisms
all have their, issues.
for example, AI code review, it can
definitely help you to read the code
and find potential issues behind the
scene, yeah, between lines of the code.
But the main problem is code
reviewers, especially AI code review,
usually does not run your app.
So it cannot see those runtime issues
after this, the app got server And
for letting AI to write it, to write
its own unit tests, it also have
potential issues because usually unit
tests reflect the code, not the spec.
Spec is basically, product requirements.
So if there's a wrong assumption
or if there's any mistakes that's
already made during the designing,
then it's very hard to be captured by
unit tests Integration test, better.
that's also why we highly recommend
always run integration tests before
you release your code to your
customers, to your production.
It can definitely catches
issues, but the only problem
is you need to keep running it.
I remember actually even a year ago,
Andrew, who used to be co-founder of
Google Brain, already emphasized that
coding, agentic coding and agentic
software testing, they should go together.
Agentic coding, I believe everybody
is already super familiar, but
agentic testing, I think is still a
very kinda unfamiliar term for lots
of enterprises and encoders today.
Agentic coding can make lots of mistakes.
everybody right now knows AI,
you cannot fully trust AI.
But not so many enterprises today, and
only a very low percentage of enterprises
are really adopting agentic testing today
to find bugs and issues introduced by your
cloud code or maybe by your codex and fix
them before release to your customers.
This is why integration
testing for AI-generated code
is a must-have today in 2026.
back to today's topic.
What I wanted to share is
verification is actually changing.
The way we test the software is evolving
due to right now no one is writing code.
It's AI is writing code.
So how we test it and also when we
should test it is changing as well.
Verification somehow is moving out of the
gate that it used to be, like in your…
Especially the last gate, like in your
slightly before your deployment, towards
moving into the loop, into the agent's
own loop during its implementation.
To well demonstrate our opinions
and also, to just give you a better
vivid, understanding about our points,
a couple months ago, our company
has ran an interesting experiment.
We call it CodeCap experiment.
Right now it's also open
source in the public right now.
We asked several frontier agents to
build the same project from the same
requirements and watch how it turns,
turn out The results was, were quite
interesting, and we found lots of,
conclusions that we never imagined before.
First, this is a high level,
result that you can see.
We ask the different kinds of
agent from those famous coding
agent providers to do a task.
actually, at that time, two,
three months ago, that was when
the World Cup was being held.
So we asked all these coding
agent to write an web application
to predict the World Cup's final
result, who will be the champion,
and also for each game, who will win.
Roughly that kind of prediction,
website to help people to understand
who could be the final winner
about that, that, Cup game.
And, we used another third-party testing
agent that we built to, to be a referee,
so that every time when those coding agent
finished implementing, some features,
the referee, the testing agent could
get involved and then quickly verify how
many features are indeed delivered and
how many of them failed to be delivered.
So first conclusion that we find
out very surprising is the loop
literally lifts every agent.
so some agent that at first got about
80% of these tasks right on the first
try after the, referee agent, the
testing agent got involved and telling
them what's wrong, what are the errors,
what are the issues behind the scene,
and also what tests somehow got failed.
After those like fix, got applied, the
result is getting better and better.
In total, we ran about
10 phases, 10 iterations.
So at the last iteration, majority
of those coding agent, as you can
see from the diagram here, reached
around 94, 95% of, of the accuracy.
we can basically observe that the accuracy
and the, correctness is rising, inside
the loop And the second thing, and
also very interesting result, is that
the loop matters more than the model.
So based on our experiment, we found
that agent that finished with the highest
correctness score started actually
almost near the bottom on the first try.
And at last, after it correct its
own behavior, after getting all the
feedback from the testing agent,
the score getting higher and higher.
And at last, it even beat
those most expensive agent.
So in our experiment, the one
that get the best score is one
actually with the cheapest price.
So essentially, you don't have
to pay the most in, if you're
using those kind of loop in order
to achieve the best performance.
The third conclusion is every agent will
tends to break its own work at some time.
So from our observation, each agent
broke features it already had gotten
working around 40 times in the loop.
Cheap one does it, expensive ones
also will make those kind of mistakes,
basically what we call regressions.
And every break stays hidden until the
app got ran and all those integration
point out those bugs and failures
Based on that, we find that verifying
inside the loop is very critical today.
Because every time when the coding
agent made some implementation,
the issues, the regressions, and
the bugs could already be there.
If you keep letting your, for example,
Cloud Code or Codex iterating without
correcting those behaviors, without fixing
those bugs or issues, then it will just
go further and further away from your
initial requirement or making the bugs
or risks become hidden deeper and deeper.
That's why, I believe even the Cloud
or Anthropic's own team recently
suggesting that you should focus
more on building the loop instead
of, building the requirements.
Because loop today, and especially
this year, matters more compared
with how you actually let your
coding agent to do the work.
Building a loop essentially is you
should design how you let the agent
to read your requirements, how you let
the coding agent to write the code, and
also how it can verify its own work.
Yeah.
And also, a second suggestion we
are given is keep every test it
verifies to stay in your workspace.
Because if loop is important, if in
each iteration you can generate some
test cases, you can write some new maybe
integration test for UI, for backend,
then these assets are actually very
valuable for future iterations as well.
Don't just throw them
away, don't waste them.
Keep storing those tests during
the loop in each iterations.
And that way, with the more iterations
and phases you get, you will find
your test suite is also growing
together with your code base.
So you don't have to worry about the
code or the entire project got more and
more complex anymore because your soft…
your test suite and your
testing, also is growing.
It has more test cases being added into
the project so that future features and
the previous, maybe edge cases, those
corner cases will all get verified once
you run all of them in each iterations.
Yeah.
And, how does this solve the existing
verification problem that we have?
it's also becoming clear, because first is
right now there is, there is a estimation
that, if you wanted to run a testing
agent, it usually don't take a lot of
time Coding agent write code very fast.
Lots of people used to find that
testing agent will take a lot of time.
Sometimes, execution could take hours.
Integration tests was--
took a lot of time.
But today, due to that, we have lots
of efficient infra, lots of cloud,
actually optimization mechanisms.
So even running like hundreds of test
cases in the cloud won't take too long.
W-- Based on our, observation through
lots of enterprises that we worked with,
it usually takes just about 10 minutes.
So that is saying you shouldn't
skip those 10 minutes or 20 minutes
anymore in 2026 for your development
because it's very little time.
And if you skip that, once you run
into bugs after you deploy your
software to a customer, that actually
will be even more cost in the future.
And the second thing is, usually
those testing solution and usually
those loop is fully automated.
So human beings normally does not
need to be engaged in those loop.
After we design the loop, after
we integrate those right tools in
the loop, all these things could
be automatically driven and run.
It could be integrated using the CLI,
the MCP, maybe it can be done cheaply
using GitHub Actions or GitHub Apps
every time when you submit new PRs.
But essentially those loop or those
CI/CD is fully automated, and ideally
it won't cost you too much time,
personally from the human perspective.
Third thing is, nowadays these solutions
are also becoming very, affordable.
as we all know, testing used
to spend, to took like lots of
teams over thousand, maybe even
tens of thousand dollars a month.
But right now, similar to cloud code,
Codex, or those coding agent, we're
seeing more and more testing agent,
agentic testing tools in the market
today with a very friendly, pricing.
It's way less than $100,
probably sometimes 20, 50.
You can already have a efficient
and, working testing agent.
Yeah.
The last thing is normally these
solution don't require too much coding,
testing, or QA knowledge, as a user.
That's why we highly recommend each
enterprise should seriously consider
this and adopt those verification layer
into your existing CI/CD, into your
existing coding or development cycles
so that it can form a complete loop.
Yeah.
Thank you.
That's basically, my sharing today,
and hope that every company will have
high quality software in the future,
and coding will also not be a pain
anymore for each of the developer.